Byzantine Institute, Inc. Dumbarton Oaks Research Library and Collection. The Byzantine Institute and Dumbarton Oaks Fieldwork Records and Papers, ca. late 1920s-2000s: Finding Aid
Image Collections and Fieldwork Archives, Dumbarton Oaks Research Library and Collection
- Administrative Records, 1920s - 2000s, MS.BZ.004-01; 28 boxes including 333 folders
  - Correspondence, ca. 1920s - 2000s, MS.BZ.004-01-01; 20 boxes including 280 folders
    - Correspondence, 1970s-1980s, MS.BZ.004-01-01-08; 1 box including 16 folders
      - Correspondence with Giles Constable, December 1977 - March 1981, MS.BZ.004-01-01-08-263; 1 folder
        Relates to the missing Red Sea Monasteries materials. Also includes a photocopy of the article "The Martyria of Saints: The wallpaintings of the Church of St. Anthony in the Eastern Desert", by Otto F.A. Meinardus from the 'Medieval and Middle Eastern Studies: In honor of Aziz Suryal Atiya', 1972.
        Otto F.A. Meinardus, "The Martyria of Saints: The wallpaintings of the Church of St. Anthony in the Eastern Desert", from the 'Medieval and Middle Eastern Studies: In honor of Aziz Suryal Atiya', 1972.
      - Correspondence between Giles Constable and Richard Martin Harrison, January 1978 - January 1982, MS.BZ.004-01-01-08-264; 1 folder
        Relates to the publication of Saraçhane materials and fieldwork at Alakilise in Lycia (Southern Anatolia). Also includes a preliminary report entitled "The Alakilise Valley in Lycia, 1977" by Harrison.
      - Correspondence between Dumbarton Oaks (e.g. John Meyendorff, Giles Constable, and Irina Andreescu), March 1978, MS.BZ.004-01-01-08-265; 1 folder
        Relates to the final campaign to restore the mosaics in the southwest room of the Hagia Sophia. Also includes letters related to the Halebiyeh fortification in Syria.
        John Meyendorff a priest, theologian, and historian of the Eastern Orthodox Church
        Meyendorff, John, 1926-1992
      - Correspondence from John Ward-Perkins to Dimitri Obolensky, March 1978, MS.BZ.004-01-01-08-266; 1 folder
        Includes meeting minutes and a scheme for the publication of the Saraçhane materials in two volumes
        John Bryan Ward-Perkins was a British architectural historian and archaeologist, who served as director of the British School at Rome from 1945-1974.
        Ward-Perkins, John, 1912-1981
        Obolensky, Dimitri, 1918-2001
      - Correspondence with Giles Constable, July - October 1978, MS.BZ.004-01-01-08-267; 1 folder
        Relates to the publication of Saraçhane and Kalenderhane Camii materials
      - Correspondence between Richard Anderson and Giles Constable, September 1978 - March 1981, MS.BZ.004-01-01-08-269; 1 folder
        Refers to photographic equipment
      - Correspondence with Giles Constable, August - November 1978, MS.BZ.004-01-01-08-268; 1 folder
      - Correspondence between Giles Constable, Ülkü Izmirligil, and Nezih Firatli, MS.BZ.004-01-01-08-270; 1 folder
        Relates to Izmirligil's employment with Dumbarton Oaks
        İzmirligil, Ülkü
      - Correspondence between Gail Carlson and Lucy Baglia, January 1979 - March 1980, MS.BZ.004-01-01-08-271; 1 folder
        Refers to financial matters
        Gail Carlson studied animal bones at Dibsi Faraj, ca. late 1970s
        Carlson, Gail
      - Correspondence between Dumbarton Oaks (e.g. Charlotte Kroll Burk) and the University of Chicago Press, May 1980 - April 1986, MS.BZ.004-01-01-08-272; 1 folder
        Relates to reproduction tests of the San Marco transparencies
        Charlotte Kroll Burk was a photograph archivist at Dumbarton Oaks
        Burk, Charlotte Kroll
        University of Chicago Press, 1891-
      - Correspondence between Dumbarton Oaks (e.g. Charlotte Kroll Burk), the University of Chicago Press and Otto Demus, January 1981 - June 1985, MS.BZ.004-01-01-08-273; 1 folder
        Born in Austria, Otto Demus was a Byzantine art historian and a scholar of the Church of San Marco in Venice, Italy. He received his doctorate from the University of Vienna. At Dumbarton Oaks, he served as a Visiting Scholar in 1949, 1953, 1958, 1960, 1965, 1973–1979, and 1981. In 1973, Dumbarton Oaks provided support for Demus for his research project at San Marco, which resulted in the two-volume publication Mosaics of San Marco in Venice (Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1984).
        Demus, Otto, 1902-1990
    - Correspondence, 1980s-2006, MS.BZ.004-01-01-09; 1 box including 7 folders
      - Correspondence between Giles Constable and Richard Martin Harrison, July 1981 - January 1987Bulk: July 1981 - January 1984, MS.BZ.004-01-01-09-274; 1 folder
        Refers to the publication of Saraçhane materials and fieldwork at Alakilise in Lycia (Southern Anatolia)
      - Correspondence from Dumbarton Oaks (e.g. Robert Thomson and Ihor Ševčenko) to Cyril Mango, September - October 1986, MS.BZ.004-01-01-09-275; 1 folder
        Refers to iconography of Byzantine art
        Robert William Thomson served as Director of the Dumbarton Oaks Research Library and Collection from 1984–1989
        A Byzantinist, philologist, and historian, Ihor Ševčenko extensively photographed Byzantine written culture mostly in the form of manuscripts and inscriptions. He participated in the Princeton-Michigan-Alexandria expedition to Mount Sinai in 1963, where he photographed and studied the manuscripts and inscriptions at Saint Catherine's Monastery.
        Thomson, Robert, 1934-
      - Correspondence about a proposed exhibit for the Sardis Expedition, 1984 - 1986, MS.BZ.004-01-01-09-276; 1 folder
      - Articles about the death of Ernest Hawkins, 1993, MS.BZ.004-01-01-09-278; 1 folder
      - Correspondence from Father Justin to Carroll F. Wales, April 1997 - June 1999, MS.BZ.004-01-01-09-279; 1 folder
        Includes a narrative about the restoration of mosaics at the Monastery of St. Catherine in Mount Sinai by Carroll Wales
        Father Justin is a Greek Orthodox monk and librarian at St. Catherine's Monastery, Mt. Sinai
        Justin, Father, St. Catherine's Monastery, 1949-
      - Correspondence between David Winfield and Annemarie Carr, October - November 2006, MS.BZ.004-01-01-09-280; 1 folder
        Refers to Dumbarton Oaks projects in Cyprus during the 1960's
        Annemarie Weyl Carr is an American Byzantinist and former Dumbarton Oaks Fellow
        Carr, Annemarie Weyl, 1941-
      - Correspondence with Henry Maguire, January 1992 - April 1998, MS.BZ.004-01-01-09-277; 1 folder
        Refers to the publication of Kalenderhane materials
        Henry Maguire conducted three campaigns to study the mosaics at the cathedral in Poreč with Ann Terry in 1997, 1999, and 2000. Their fieldwork resulted in the publication Dynamic Splendor: The Wall Mosaics in the Cathedral of Eufrasius at Poreč (University Park, PA: Pennsylvania State University Press, 2007). At Dumbarton Oaks, Maguire was a Junior Fellow (1971-1972), a member of the Board of Senior Fellows (1986-1990 and 1991-1996 ex officio), Visiting Senior Research Associate (1989-1990), and Director of Studies (1991-1996) in the Byzantine Studies Program.
        Maguire, Henry, 1943-
  - Financial Records, ca. 1930s - 1960s, MS.BZ.004-01-02; 4 boxes including 30 folders
    Series II contains financial reports, logbooks, bank statements, vouchers, and checks. It documents the financial history of the fieldwork projects executed by the Byzantine Institute and Dumbarton Oaks between the 1930s and 1960s.
    Arranged by the type of creation in chronological order (for instance, the vouchers from the Paris Office are grouped together in sequential order).
    - Financial Documents, 1930s - 1950s, MS.BZ.004-01-02-01; 1 box including 10 folders
      Contains financial reports, logbooks, statements of deposits, expenditures, and a list of salaries per fieldworker. These materials illustrate the administrative and financial history of the Byzantine Institute.
      - “ACCOUNT OF ADVANCES paid by Mr. Whittemore at Istanbul in 1934”, 1934, MS.BZ.004-01-02-01-281; 1 folder
        Title from first page: “Statement of account of Advances of pay made by Mr. Whittemore to the Technical Staff at St. Sophia. Istanbul. 1934.”
      - “Payments 1935”, 1935, MS.BZ.004-01-02-01-282; 1 folder
      - "1938 Book of Advances", 1936 - 1938, MS.BZ.004-01-02-01-283; 1 folder
        Title from first page: "Advances of money made to staff. 1936"
      - "St. Sophia Museum. 1937. Advances of wages paid to: J. Brennan, G.H. Flockton, R. Gregory, W. Gregory", 1937, MS.BZ.004-01-02-01-284; 1 folder
      - "Record of the withdrawals of wages of the staff at St. Sophia. Istanbul during 1938", 1938, MS.BZ.004-01-02-01-285; 1 folder
      - Correspondence between Dumbarton Oaks (e.g. John Thacher, Paul Underwood) and the Byzantine Institute (e.g. Seth Gano), June 1943 - January 1952, MS.BZ.004-01-02-01-286; 1 folder
      - Correspondence and receipts of contributions, 1932 - 1937, MS.BZ.004-01-02-01-287; 1 folder
      - Financial reports and memoranda October 1950 - 1956, MS.BZ.004-01-02-01-288; 1 folder
        Cash receipts and disbursements. Also includes memos and minutes related to the Byzantine Institute library.
      - Financial reports and memoranda, April 1951 - January 1956, MS.BZ.004-01-02-01-289; 1 folder
        Includes a copy of the Byzantine Institute by-laws
        Byzantine Institute, Inc.
      - Financial statements, travel expenses, budget, and contributor lists, April 1951 - 1960, MS.BZ.004-01-02-01-290; 1 folder
        Includes a Certificate of Vote declaring John Thacher as the new Treasurer of the Byzantine Institute
    - Financial Documents, 1950s - 1960s, MS.BZ.004-01-02-02; 1 box including 10 folders
      - Income tax forms and withholding tax statements, April 1951 - 1961, MS.BZ.004-01-02-02-291; 1 folder
        Includes a letter stating that Paul Underwood is the new Field Director of the Byzantine institute
      - Correspondence, invoices, and shipping orders, April 1953 - July 1956, MS.BZ.004-01-02-02-292; 1 folder
      - Check book and bank statements, January 1954 - June 1955, MS.BZ.004-01-02-02-293; 1 folder
      - Bank statements of receipts and expenditures, January 1954 - December 1955, MS.BZ.004-01-02-02-294; 1 folder
      - Bank statements of receipts and disbursements, January 1955 - January 1956, MS.BZ.004-01-02-02-295; 1 folder
      - Financial statements, reports, minutes, and lists, 1956 - July 1963, MS.BZ.004-01-02-02-296; 1 folder
      - Paris office vouchers (receipts, reports, pay stubs, etc.), July - December 1954, MS.BZ.004-01-02-02-297; 1 folder; Folders 297-300: For consistency, vouchers from the Paris Office are grouped together in sequential order.
      - Paris office: Financial statements, January 1955 - July 1955, MS.BZ.004-01-02-02-298; 1 folder
      - Paris office: Financial statements, July 1955 - December 1955, MS.BZ.004-01-02-02-299; 1 folder
      - Original folders for Paris Library vouchers, 1955, MS.BZ.004-01-02-02-300; 1 folder
        Folder is titled, "Paris Library Vouchers for 1955"
    - Bank Account Statements, Early 1950s - 1960s, MS.BZ.004-01-02-03; 1 box including 4 folders
      - Bank statements and checks, March 1952 - October 1955, MS.BZ.004-01-02-03-301; 1 folder
      - Receipts for deposits to and withdrawals from the Byzantine Institute bank account, March 1952 - January 1958, MS.BZ.004-01-02-03-302; 1 folder
        Includes a letter about opening a bank account for the Byzantine Institute
      - Bank statements and receipts of payment to the Byzantine Institute, December 1956 - January 1957, MS.BZ.004-01-02-03-303; 1 folder
      - Bank statements, correspondence, and receipts for deposits to and withdrawals from the Byzantine Institute account, January 1957 - 1965, MS.BZ.004-01-02-03-304; 1 folder
    - Bank Account Statements, Late 1950s - 1960s, MS.BZ.004-01-02-04; 1 box including 6 folders
      - Bank statements and checks withdrawn from the Byzantine Institute bank account, January 1958 - May 1960, MS.BZ.004-01-02-04-305; 1 folder
      - Bank statements and checks withdrawn from the Byzantine Institute bank account, December 1958 - December 1959, MS.BZ.004-01-02-04-306; 1 folder
      - Bank statements and checks withdrawn from the Byzantine Institute bank account, December 1959 - April 1960, MS.BZ.004-01-02-04-307; 1 folder
      - Bank statements and checks withdrawn from the Byzantine Institute bank account, April 1960 - December 1961, MS.BZ.004-01-02-04-308; 1 folder
      - Bank statements and receipts of payments to the Byzantine Institute, December 1961 - February 1963, MS.BZ.004-01-02-04-309; 1 folder
      - Bank statements and checks withdrawn from the Byzantine Institute bank account, January 1954 - February 1956, MS.BZ.004-01-02-04-310; 1 folder
  - Logbooks, ca. 1930s - 1960s, MS.BZ.004-01-03; 2 boxes including 8 folders
    Contains logbooks of purchases for the Byzantine Institute Library in Paris between the 1930s and 1950s, which record the resources used by Institute staff and researchers. This series also contains records of visitors to Kariye Camii, Istanbul, during the 1950s and 1960s.
    Arranged by the type of creation in sequential order.
    - Logbooks of Purchased Books for the Byzantine Institute Library in Paris, ca. 1930s - 1950s, MS.BZ.004-01-03-01; 1 box including 4 folders
      - Logbook of books received, 1932 - 1934, MS.BZ.004-01-03-01-311; 1 folder
      - Logbook of books received, 1934 - 1947, MS.BZ.004-01-03-01-312; 1 folder
      - Logbook of books received, 1947-1950, MS.BZ.004-01-03-01-313; 1 folder
      - "List of Persons to Whom the Hagia Sophia Album of Mosaics Has Been Sent", 1950 -1951, MS.BZ.004-01-03-01-314; 1 folder
    - Guestbooks, 1950s -1960s, MS.BZ.004-01-03-02; 1 box including 4 folders
      - Guestbook, Kariye Camii, 1953 - 1957, MS.BZ.004-01-03-02-315; 1 folder
        Donated by Ercüment Atabay on May 19, 2011
      - Guestbook, Kariye Camii, 1958 - 1960, MS.BZ.004-01-03-02-316; 1 folder
        Physical characteristics and technical requirements
        In November 2011, the guestbook received conservation treatment for a missing spine; the existing binding was retained and repaired and the spine was strengthened.
        Donated by Ercüment Atabay on May 19, 2011.
      - Four blank papers with the Byzantine Institute letterhead, undated, Undated, MS.BZ.004-01-03-02-317; 1 folder
      - Miscellaneous: 2 small booklets of general photograph catalogues by A. Iskender, Undated, MS.BZ.004-01-03-02-318; 1 folder
        Hagop Iskender was a photographer in Istanbul and father of Pierre Iskender. Hagop was a partner in the Sebah & Joaillier studio in the early 20th century.
        Iskender, Hagop, 1871-1949
  - Publication Materials, ca. 1930's - 1960's, MS.BZ.004-01-04; 2 boxes including 14 folders; 4 wood block plates
    Series IV contains published articles by Thomas Whittemore and other authors about the art and architecture of Hagia Sophia.
    Roughly organized in chronological order.
    - Whittemore, Thomas, "Mosaics of Aya Sophia" from the Bulletin of the Archaeological Institute of Bulgaria, volume X, 1936, 1936, MS.BZ.004-01-04-319; 1 folder
    - Whittemore, Thomas, copies of "Archaeology During the Republic in Turkey", reprint from American Journal of Archaeology, volume 47, No.2, 1943, 1943, MS.BZ.004-01-04-320; 1 folder
    - Whittemore, Thomas, "On the Dating of Some Mosaics in Hagia Sophia", from The Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin, Summer 1946, 1946, MS.BZ.004-01-04-321; 1 folder
    - Whittemore, Thomas, "An Unpublished Seal of the Patriarch Ignatios" and "Moving Pictures in Colour of Portraits in Mosaic of Saints in the Church of Hagia Sophia in Constantinople", July 27 - August 2, 19481946, MS.BZ.004-01-04-322; 1 folder
      "An Unpublished Seal of the Patriarch Ignatios" is a reprint from Byzantina Metabyzantina, volume 1, part 1, 1946. "Moving Pictures in Colour of Portraits in Mosaic of Saints in the Church of Hagia Sophia in Constantinople" is an extract from the 6th International Congress of Byzantine Studies, Paris, July 27-August 2, 1948.
    - Newspaper clippings, November 1950 - April 1959, MS.BZ.004-01-04-323; 1 folder
    - Copies of Life magazine with the article: "Proud Byzantium's Christian Treasures", December 1950, MS.BZ.004-01-04-324; 1 folder
      Life Magazine
    - Copy of Archaeology magazine and article reprints, Summer 1951, MS.BZ.004-01-04-325; 1 folder
      Article reprints include: "The Uncovering of Byzantine Mosaics in Hagia Sophia", by William MacDonald, volume 4, no.2, pages 89-93, and "Hagia Sophia: The Collapse of the First Dome", by William Emerson and Robert L. Van Nice, volume 4, no. 2, pages 94-103.
      William Emerson was an American architect and Dean of the school of architecture at Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Emerson was involved in the Byzantine Institute and sponsored Robert Van Nice's survey of Hagia Sophia.
      From 1937 to 1985, Robert Van Nice conducted a large scale architectural survey of Hagia Sophia in Istanbul, Turkey. The survey was sponsored by both William Emerson, Dean Emeritus of the School of Architecture at MIT, and Dumbarton Oaks. Van Nice and his assistants produced detailed architectural plates from their fieldwork, publishing them in two installments entitled Saint Sophia in Istanbul: An Architectural Survey in 1965 and 1986.
    - Underwood, Paul, "A Preliminary Report on some Unpublished Mosaics in Hagia Sophia," American Journal of Archaeology, volume 55, no. 4, page 367, October 1951, MS.BZ.004-01-04-326; 1 folder
    - Lemerle, P., "Hommage a Thomas Whittemore," extract from Byzantion, volume 21, fasc. 1, 1951, 1951, MS.BZ.004-01-04-327; 1 folder
      Paul Lemerle was a French Byzantinist
      Lemerle, P., 1903-1989
    - Whittemore, Thomas, "A Byzantine Bronze Medallion with an Imperial Representation" from Studies in Art and Literature for Belle da Costa Greene, edited by Dorothy Miner, 1954, MS.BZ.004-01-04-328; 1 folder
    - Clère, J.J., "Comptes Rendus", 1955, MS.BZ.004-01-04-329; 1 folder
      J.J. Clère was a French Egyptologist and former Directeur d'Etudes at the Ecole Pratique des Hautes Etudes in Paris.
      Clère, J.J., 1906-1989
    - Correspondence, memorandum, and project reports, 1959, MS.BZ.004-01-04-330; 1 folder
      Includes a layout of "Quick Glimpses in a Brief Panorama of History: Looking across the blue waters of the Bosporus from ancient walls of a modern city."
    - Whittemore, Thomas, "The Byzantine Institute, Incorporated, of America", 1960, MS.BZ.004-01-04-331; 1 folder
      Cover Image: "'The First Seven Steps of the Virgin detail', Karieh Djami, Mosaic, ca. 1310."
    - Postcards of Byzantine sites and architecture, Undated, MS.BZ.004-01-04-332; 1 folder
    - Wood block plates, Summer 1951, MS.BZ.004-01-04-333; 1 box
      Four (4) wood block plates and offprints used for the cover of Archaeology magazine.
- Fieldwork Papers, 1920s -2000s, MS.BZ.004-02; 46 boxes including 494 folders; 29 boxes including 29 photo albums; 20+ oversize files; 26 boxes of backlog materials; 2 boxes including 14 folders of accumulated research materials by ICFA staff
  This subgroup highlights the research conducted by the Byzantine Institute and Dumbarton Oaks fieldwork directors and staff on Byzantine art and architecture and their fieldwork projects at Byzantine sites, such as Hagia Sophia, Kariye Camii, Kalenderhane Camii, Bargala, and others, between the 1930s and 1980s. The materials also record the fieldworkers’ day-to-day work and techniques employed on site.
  This subgroup is divided into five (5) series and organized by medium (or type of item) in chronological order.
  - Fieldwork Notebooks and Research Notes, ca. 1929-1970s, MS.BZ.004-02-01; 30 boxes containing 299 folders
    This series documents the conservation, restoration, survey, and research that were conducted by the Byzantine Institute and Dumbarton Oaks fieldwork directors and staff, including Thomas Whittemore, Paul Underwood, Nicholas Kluge, Richard A. Gregory, Ernest Hawkins, and others. The contents contain fieldwork notebooks, research and bibliographic notes, drawings, sketches, charts, and ground plans from the fieldwork projects conducted in the following locations: Egypt, Turkey, Republic of Macedonia, Cyprus, and Syria.
    Divided into 7 subseries and arranged by fieldwork order and site (and alphabetical order, if the author’s name exists).
    - Red Sea Monasteries, Egypt, ca. late 1920s-1940s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01; 2 boxes containing 34 folders
      Materials related to fieldwork conducted at the Red Sea Monasteries in Egypt from 1929-1931.
      - Photostat copy and hand-drawn map of Egypt, ca. late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-001; 1 folder
        For the reprint of a regional map entitled "El Saf," May 1914, see Subgroup 2, Series 5, Subseries 1, File 548.
      - Photographs of illustrations, late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-002; 1 folder
        Contains: "Articles Found in Museum of St. Anthony" and "Old Utensils Found in Keep St. Paul". Also includes summaries related to the drawings.
      - Frolow, Anatole, notebook: "St. Antoine", 1929-1932, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-003; 1 folder with 1 notebook
        Frolow was a Byzantine scholar affiliated with the Byzantine Institute
        Frolow, Anatole, 1906-1972
      - Notes and transcriptions of texts in English, German, and Arabic, Bulk: ca. late 1920s-1940, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-004; 1 folder
        Includes: notes on "Lustered Ware (Persian)"; descriptions of the monasteries of St. Anthony and St. Paul; and notes and typewritten estimate of expenses for publishing an album of Coptic paintings in France, May 1, 1940
      - Malinine, Michael, transcription of text:"El-Bagaouat", late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-005; 1 folder
        Michel Malinine was a French demoticist and Coptologist, who edited the second volume of The Bulletin of the Byzantine Institute
        Malinine, Michel, 1900-1977
      - Netchitailov, V., manuscript for text beginning with "Norov, the Russian traveler who visited Egypt in the years 1834 - 1835...", late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-006; 1 folder
        Vladimir Netchetailov was a writer and painter affiliated with the Byzantine Institute, ca. 1920s-1930s
      - Typewritten extracts from 'The Ancient Coptic Churches of Egypt, Vol. 1', by Alfred J. Butler, late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-007; 1 folder
        Contains:"The Church of Abu Sargah"; "The Cathedral Church of Al'Adra, Commonly called Al Mu'Allakah, or The Hanging Church"; and "Dair Abu-s-Sifain", and "Mâri Mîna".
        Alfred J. Butler was a scholar of Coptic Egypt
        Butler, Alfred J., 1850-1936
        Butler, Alfred Joshua. The Ancient Coptic Churches of Egypt. Oxford: Clarendon Press, 1884. 2 vols.
      - Typewritten extracts from 'The Ancient Coptic Churches of Egypt, Vol. 1', by Alfred J. Butler, late 1920s - early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-008; 1 folder
        Contains:"The Church of Burbarah, or St. Barbara"; "The Churches of Mari Girgis and Al'Adra", and "Coptic Art (Introduction)." Also includes a paper submitted to Professor Thomas Whittemore, "Coptic Art: Buildings in Ancient Egyptian Temples", by Bernard S, Myers, January 10, 1929.
        Bernard S. Myers was an art historian and editor who wrote on German expressionist and Mexican art. He received a doctorate from the Institute of Fine Arts at New York University, and taught at NYU, the Art Students League and City University of New York. From 1959 to 1970 he was editor in chief for art books at McGraw-Hill.
        Myers, Bernard S., 1908-1993
      - Texts from various sources, late 1920s-early 1930s, MS.BZ.004-02-01-01-009; 1 folder; Former processor noted the initials "T.W." on the back of each paper.